

https://github.com/tayyabaolakh

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tayyabaolakh036 in

Tayyab Shabbir

Full stack developer

About Me

Graduated as Software Engineer with 2 years of experience as a full stack web developer. I have been working as a freelancer for 1.5 years but tinkering since a kid. Aiming to use my knowledge at your organization that I have acquired from my coursework as well as self study. I have also worked as a UI/UX, graphic/web designer. I can help everywhere in the stack.

Furthermore, likes to read poetry and literature. Poetry have my heart.

Skills

- HTML, CSS
- Time Management
- Problem Solving
- Android and iOS App Development
- Creativity
- Google cloud platform
- Rest APIs
- Team work
- Adapdability
- Communication Skills

Expertise

- Django and Django Rest Framework
- React is
- Bootstrap
- Git and Github
- Node is
- Python
- JavaScript
- **React Native**

Reward

Nov 2021 | Bahria University

Graphic designer Photo and Video editor

Work Experience

| Present | Full stack developer Code n Creative Working on an analytic dashboard called nlaanalytics in MERN Stack. https://nlaanalytics.de.r.appspot.com/ |
|-----------|--|
| 2021-2022 | Django Backend developer Modatabs (Fiverr) |
| 3 months | Built a website for selling products in Django and React from scratch. Frontend: React js Redux Backend: Python Django Rest Framework http://modatabs.com/ |
| 2021-2022 | React Developer Holylandonclick (Fiverr) |
| 2 months | Built a tourism website in Django rest framework from scratch. Frontend: React Redux, Backend: Python & Django Rest Framework. |
| 2021-2021 | Full stack developer Intern Eziline Software House |
| 3 months | Frontend: React Redux JavaScript Material Design Backend: Python, Django Rest Framework & Redux |
| 2019-2020 | Full stack developer Naturaw |
| 1 year | Frontend: Boostrap HTML CSS JavaScript Backend: Python, Django Framework & Ajax |
| | |

Education

2018-2022

| 4 years | Bahria University Islamabad Campus |
|----------------------|---|
| 2016-2018 2 years | ICS Punjab College, Sambrial, Sialkot |
| 2014-2016 | Matric |
| 2 years | The Creative School, near Sialkot Airport |

Software Engineering

Personal Projects

PlantDoctor (Final Year Project) React Native and Flask

Built a cross platform application in React Native and flask using Transformers which detects crop or plant leaf disease with up to 98.36% accuracy.

Ecommerce website (Semester project)

Frontend: Bootstrap | HTML | CSS | JavaScript Backend: Python & Django Framework

Library Management System (Semester project)

Built a library management system in C++.